{
  "sourceFile": "2018-2019-International-Geography-Bee-Regional-Quiz-Tournament-Round-3.txt",
  "count": 10,
  "items": [
    {
      "qno": 1,
      "question": "This state’s pink granite Enchanted Rock can be found in its Edwards Plateau, while its cities of Midland and Odessa are near oil reserves in the Permian Basin. The Trinity River and Colorado River flow through major cities in this state, where Big Bend National Park, Brownsville, and El Paso are found along the Rio Grande. For the point, name this state with its capital at Austin.",
      "answer": "State of Texas"
    },
    {
      "qno": 2,
      "question": "This country’s Caruachi Dam generates hydroelectric power from the Caroni River. Many tepuis, tall table-like mountains, can be found in this country’s Guiana Highlands. This country’s Catatumbo River experiences hundreds of lightning strikes every day and feeds into its Lake Maracaibo. For the point, Angel Falls and the Orinoco River are in what country with capital Caracas?",
      "answer": "Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela"
    },
    {
      "qno": 3,
      "question": "Many members of this ethnic group live in refugee camps around the city of Cox’s Bazar. A 1982 law denied citizenship to members of this group, who live in the Rakhine State on the Andaman Sea. In 2017, the UN declared the military violence against this group a crime against humanity and criticized State Counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi for inaction. For the point, identify this Islamic ethnic group made effectively stateless by Myanmar.",
      "answer": "Rohingya"
    },
    {
      "qno": 4,
      "question": "This country’s city of Kutna Hora is home to the Sedlec Ossuary, which contains an elaborately designed chandelier made of human bones. Less macabre attractions in this country include the Charles Bridge across the Vltava River in its capital, which contains a statue of Saint Wenceslas. Moravia and Bohemia are the primary regions of this country west of Slovakia. For the point, name this Central European country with cities Brno and Prague.",
      "answer": "Czechia"
    },
    {
      "qno": 5,
      "question": "This feature’s Jinshanling [Jin-shan-ling] section crosses extremely steep slopes. Shanhai Pass, the “First Pass Under Heaven,” is near this strcuture’s end at the Bohai Sea. This structure’s native name refers to its length of ten thousand li. Its longest section stretches from Mount Hu to the Jiayu [Jah-Yu] Pass. For the point, name this 4500-mile long structure completed by Qin Shihuangdi [Chin Shuh-Hwang-Dee] in Northern China.",
      "answer": "Great Wall of China"
    },
    {
      "qno": 6,
      "question": "This country’s cuisine includes the entrees of Rfissa [Ruh-FISS-uh] and Chicken Bastilla as well as the soup Harira. Bojador and Laayoune are cities controlled by this country in a territory disputed by the Polisario Front. Marrakesh and Casablanca are in this country, which serves as the western terminus of the Atlas Mountains. For the point, name this country with its capital at Rabat.",
      "answer": "Kingdom of Morocco"
    },
    {
      "qno": 7,
      "question": "This city’s Ajyad Fortress was destroyed to construct the world’s largest clock face and the Abraj Al Bait Towers. A structure in this city is covered by the Kiswah and cleaned twice a year with rose water. That edifice stands 20 meters away from this city’s Well of Zamzam. In this city, a black cube in the Great Mosque is circled seven times during the Hajj. For the point, name this holiest city in Islam.",
      "answer": "Mecca"
    },
    {
      "qno": 8,
      "question": "This island’s Chudu Region contains the Akaishi Mountains, which lie south of its Hida and Kiso Mountains. This island’s Tohoku Region contains the Miyagi and Fukushima Prefectures. Hokusai’s South Wind, Clear Sky depicts this island’s Mount Fuji, and its Kanto region includes the city of Yokohama. For the point, Tokyo is on what largest and most populous Japanese island?",
      "answer": "Honshu"
    },
    {
      "qno": 9,
      "question": "The city of Vladikavkaz lies on the Terek River in this mountain range. This mountain range’s largest lake, Lake Sevan, is east of Mount Aragats. Autonomous regions on this range’s northern slopes include Nagorno-Karabakh and Dagestan. This range also contains Chechnya, a Russian subject west of the Caspian Sea. Mount Elbrus is the highest point of, for the point, what mountain range separating Europe from Asia?",
      "answer": "Caucasus Mountains"
    },
    {
      "qno": 10,
      "question": "The Lady and the Unicorn tapestries can be found in this city’s Museum of the Middle Ages, which was formerly the Cluny Museum. A former train station in this city now houses Impressionist art as the Musée d’Orsay. This city’s Tuileries [TOOL er ies] Gardens are adjacent to a museum served by a large glass pyramid designed by I.M. Pei [Pay]. For the point, name this city home to the Louvre.",
      "answer": "Paris"
    }
  ]
}